Noa Garcia Docampo

Address Aston University Personal website www.noagarciad.com
Birmingham, B4 7ET Email garciadn@aston.ac.uk

Room MB209 **Nationality** Spanish

Personal Profile

I am a second year PhD student in computer science at Aston University, United Kingdom, under the supervision of Dr. George Vogiatzis. My research interests include computer vision and machine learning applied to large-scale image and video retrieval.

Education

2015-? PhD in Computer Science - Aston University, Birmingham, United Kingdom

2006-2012 Telecommunications Engineering (5 years degree) - Universitat Politecnica de Catalunya,

Barcelona, Spain

Research Experience

Oct 2015 - PhD Candidate

Present Aston University, Birmingham, United Kingdom

Image and Video Retrieval in Large Scale Datasets.

Feb 2013 - Researcher hired for a project
Jan 2015 Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Computer vision applied to parking scenes. WePark project founded by the Spanish Ministry of

Industry, Tourism and Commerce under the Project reference TSI-020100-2011-57.

Nov 2011 - Student Placement

May 2012 Gradiant - Centro Tecnologico de Telecomunicaciones

Final degree project: Heart Rate estimation using facial video information.

Work Experience

Jan 2016 - Teaching Assistant
Present Aston University

Assisting in labs, tutorials and marking with BSc Computer Science modules, including:

• Jan 2017 - Mar 2017 CS2420 Computer Animation

Jan 2016 - Mar 2016

• Oct 2016 - Dec 2016 CS2150 Computer Graphics

• Oct 2016 - Dec 2016 CS3360 Software Project Management

Feb 2015 - Vision Engineer Sep 2016 Zap to Buy

Designing a retrieval system for finding video frames from smartphone images.

Nov 2012 - Computer Vision Engineer

Jan 2013 Shot & Shop

Designing an object recognition tool for finding products from smartphone images.

Oct 2012 - Software Engineer

Jan 2013 H.I. Iberia, Ingeniería y Proyectos

Implementation of state-of-the-art facial recognition techniques.

Publications

- Noa Garcia, George Vogiatzis. **Exploiting Redundancy in Binary Features for Image Retrieval in Large-Scale Video Collections**. European Conference on Visual Media Production (CVMP), 2016.
- Nuria Sánchez, Noa García, Jose Manuel Menéndez. **Feedback-based parameterized strategies for improving performance of video surveillance understanding frameworks**. 14th Ibero-American Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IBERAMIA), 2014.
- Carmen Bravo, Nuria Sánchez, Noa García and Jose Manuel Menendez. **Outdoor Vacant Parking Space Detector for improving mobility in Smart Cities**. Portuguese Conference on Artificial Intelligence (EPIA), 2013.

Skills

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, PHP

Operating Systems: Unix, Windows

Software: Matlab, Qt Creator, Android Studio, Eclipse Libraries: OpenCV, MatConvNet, Eigen, Boost

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Office Tools: MTeX, Microsoft Office, Open Office, Photoshop, Gimp

Languages

Spanish: Native Catalan: Native

English: Fluent (written and spoken)

Japanese: Basic

Awards

Dec 2016 Atos IT Challenge 2017

Member of one of the shortlisted teams for the development phase.